<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paul.annesley.cc</title>
    <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on paul.annesley.cc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 23:15:27 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://paul.annesley.cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MailHog on ECS &#43; Service Discovery &#43; CloudFormation</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/ecs-service-discovery-cloudformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 23:15:27 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/ecs-service-discovery-cloudformation/</guid>
      <description>AWS announced Service Discovery for ECS a few months ago. It builds upon the Route 53 Auto Naming API announced a few months before that.
Clear documentation and examples for using it with CloudFormation are currently hard to find. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small but complete example of an ECS Service on Fargate using Service Discovery for internal and external discovery.
I&amp;rsquo;m using the fake/development mail server MailHog as an example. Thanks to David&amp;nbsp;Looi at Culture&amp;nbsp;Amp for his contributions to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS X: launchd is cool</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/09/mac-os-x-launchd-is-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 01:22:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/09/mac-os-x-launchd-is-cool/</guid>
      <description>One of the core components of Mac OS X is launchd, and it turns out it can do some cool things.
I particularly like the idea of using QueueDirectories to monitor and act upon files dropped into a directory, without having to run any extra daemons. The files could be uploaded to S3, transcoded to a different video format, gzipped… anything.
Anyway, I recently fell into the launchd documentation, and came out with this write-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Dependency Injection and MiniTest::Mock</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/03/simple-dependency-injection-and-minitest-mock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 19:53:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/03/simple-dependency-injection-and-minitest-mock/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a Ruby client for Amazon Alexa&amp;rsquo;s APIs, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d
pull out an example of nice, simple dependency injection to facilitate unit
testing. Nothing revolutionary or complicated, just good practice.
The example is based around a UriSigner class, normally used by the calling
code like this:
UriSigner.new(*credentials).sign_uri(uri) The calling code doesn&amp;rsquo;t know or care that UriSigner depends on Base64,
OpenSSL::Digest::SHA256 and OpenSSL::HMAC. The unit test for
UriSigner, however, cares for two reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast RSpec/Rails: tiered spec_helper.rb</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/03/fast-rspec-slash-rails-tiered-spec-helper-dot-rb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 20:41:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/03/fast-rspec-slash-rails-tiered-spec-helper-dot-rb/</guid>
      <description>Slow Rails startup time is the TDD killer.
paul@paulbookpro ~/project ⸩ time rspec spec/lib/method_hunting_delegator_spec.rb .. Finished in 0.00078 seconds 2 examples, 0 failures rspec spec/lib/method_hunting_delegator_spec.rb -f d 6.76s user 1.64s system 91% cpu 9.225 total  Holy crap, that&amp;rsquo;s 9 seconds of Rails startup, for 0.00078 seconds worth of
RSpec. And this class/test doesn&amp;rsquo;t even use Rails! We can do better.
The culprit? That require &amp;quot;spec_helper&amp;quot; at the top of every spec file which</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MethodHuntingDelegator</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/01/methodhuntingdelegator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 17:51:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2012/01/methodhuntingdelegator/</guid>
      <description>I was implementing search in a Ruby app where the results objects were instances
of a mix of model classes. Each one had what could be considered a title and a
description, but the method names were inconsistent.
Wrapping each result in a SearchResult decorator to normalize the interface
seemed like a good idea. Ruby provides an abstract Delegator and a concrete
SimpleDelegator which gets most of the way there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An intro to modern OpenGL</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2010/05/opengl-es-20-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 22:29:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2010/05/opengl-es-20-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>An excellent OpenGL tutorial; beware other documentation and tutorials which endorse deprecated APIs and practices.
Modern enough to be applicable to OpenGL ES 2.0 (and therefore WebGL), which requires vertex and fragment shaders to be written in OpenGL Shader Language to take advantage of the programmable rendering pipeline, and which removes much of the procedural (glBegin/glEnd) API.
Adapting this tutorial to Cocoa Touch for iPhone/iPad OpenGL ES 2.0 development was relatively easy, and beat any iPhone OS specific documentation for ES 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git-ff for git 1.7&#43;</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2010/05/git-ff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 21:07:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2010/05/git-ff/</guid>
      <description>Provides git ff to quickly fast-forward your current branch to the tracked remote when possible.
It&amp;rsquo;s git pull --ff-only for those who do their own fetching, and besides, git ff is quicker :)
Drop it in your path somewhere; depends on Git 1.7+ for the new &amp;ndash;ff-only parameter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict free DNS and routes with multiple DHCP interfaces</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2009/10/conflict-free-dns-routes-multiple-dhcp-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2009 11:57:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2009/10/conflict-free-dns-routes-multiple-dhcp-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Running DHCP on two or more network interfaces inevitably leads to conflicting or unpredictable DNS and default route settings.
For development at home and work, I use an Ubuntu virtual machine running on Mac OS. To ensure I have a predictable IP address regardless of what network I&#39;m on, the VM primary network interface is NATed, so it gets an IP address from VMware&#39;s DHCP server. To let my co-workers access HTTP on my virtual machine, I have a second network interface which is bridged</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quote from Guido van Rossum</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2009/02/guido-van-rossum-owned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 22:11:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2009/02/guido-van-rossum-owned/</guid>
      <description>Although I had hoped to provide something similar in Python, it quickly became clear that such an approach would be impossible because there was no way to elegantly distinguish instance variables from local variables in a language without variable declarations.
 &amp;#8212; Guido van Rossum, The History of Python: Adding Support for User-defined Classes
# The Greeter class class Greeter def initialize(name) @name = name.capitalize end def salute puts &amp;#34;Hello #{@name}!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quote from _why</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2009/01/why-x86/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 15:00:37 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2009/01/why-x86/</guid>
      <description>On a related note, I would like to say something to all of the parties working on languages atop abstracted runtimes, such as the JVM and .Net and Parrot.
The first thing is: you should try targetting x86. It&#39;s very popular!
 &amp;#8212; why the lucky stiff, potion INTERNALS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI History Meme</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/12/cli-history-meme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 13:35:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/12/cli-history-meme/</guid>
      <description>I just came across Rob Hudson&#39;s Command Line History, which in turn reminded me of Mark Pilgrim&#39;s History meme from back in April.
After waiting a fashionably-late eight months, I&#39;ll use this as an excuse to find out if I can still publish to my site since hastily patching it up to Django 1.0 three months ago. I suspect that says something about my technology vs. writing priorities.
paul@macbuntupro:~$ uname -a Linux macbuntupro 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git rebase --interactive</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/07/git-rebase-acid-chainsaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 01:53:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/07/git-rebase-acid-chainsaw/</guid>
      <description>And then there’s git rebase --interactive, which is a bit like git commit --amend hopped up on acid and holding a chainsaw — completely insane and quite dangerous but capable of exposing entirely new states of mind.
 — Ryan Tomayko, The Thing About Git</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexihash - Consistent Hashing for PHP</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/04/flexihash-consistent-hashing-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 23:43:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/04/flexihash-consistent-hashing-php/</guid>
      <description>After reading Tom Kleinpeter&amp;#039;s article on consistent hashing last month, I was inspired to write Flexihash, an open source consistent hashing implementation for PHP, as I couldn&amp;#039;t see anything decent around that fit the bill.
But first, a little bit of background and a use case example. C&amp;#039;mon, humor me&amp;hellip;
Balancing Act There&amp;#039;s a few reasons why a large website would want to spread their images (and other resources) out across several URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schneier on Security: The Value of Privacy</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/01/schneier-value-of-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 01:52:05 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2008/01/schneier-value-of-privacy/</guid>
      <description>My problem with quips like these – as right as they are – is that they accept the premise that privacy is about hiding a wrong. It’s not. Privacy is an inherent human right, and a requirement for maintaining the human condition with dignity and respect.
 — Schneier on Security: The Value of Privacy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django and Python Imaging Library (PIL) on Leopard</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/11/django-and-python-imaging-library-pil-on-leopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 13:05:46 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/11/django-and-python-imaging-library-pil-on-leopard/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5 of the excellent Django Book makes use of django.db.models.URLField().
When running under the default Python 2.5 environment shipped with Mac OS 10.5 Leopard, this causes an error something along these lines:
$ ./manage.py validate Error: One or more models did not validate: books.author: &amp;#34;headshot&amp;#34;: To use ImageFields, you need to install the Python Imaging Library. Get it at http://www.pythonware.com/products/pil/ . Assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve installed XCode (go on, you know you want to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Webate - Tables Have No Place In Web Page Layout</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/08/great-webate-tables-have-no-place-in-web-page-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2007 05:35:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/08/great-webate-tables-have-no-place-in-web-page-layout/</guid>
      <description>As promised, I&#39;m finally posting my notes from my second debate in the Melbourne Web Standards Group&#39;s first ever Great Webate.
The proposition was that Tables Still Have A Place In Web Page Layout, and it was up to James Edwards and I to convince the crowd that such a statement just wasn&#39;t going to fly in the 21st century. Our unfortunate opponents were Kevin Yank and Andrew Krespanis, and I must say they made a brave albeit sometimes desperate attempt, given the proposition and the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Webate - Ajax Not The Future Of The Web</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/08/great-webate-ajax-not-the-future-of-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2007 14:40:19 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/08/great-webate-ajax-not-the-future-of-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Last night was the Melbourne Web Standards Group&#39;s first ever Great Webate. I teamed up with Kevin Yank to argue against the proposition That Ajax Is The Future Of The Web, with James Edwards and Andrew Krespanis arguing the affirmative. As the first negative speaker, my argument went something like this...
I&#39;m sorry to be the one to break it to you all, but Ajax is not the future of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xdebug 2.0.0 Released</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/07/xdebug-200-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 14:55:19 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/07/xdebug-200-released/</guid>
      <description>This one nearly slipped past me, what with the lack of any RSS/Atom feeds on http://xdebug.org/, so I figured I should put it in one.
Xdebug 2.0.0 final has been released.
After almost four years of work, Xdebug 2 is finally ready. With improved functionality and many new features it is ready to totally change the way you develop in PHP. Some of the new features and updates include improved stack traces, execution traces to files, code coverage analysis and much improved remote debugging support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP 5.2.1 bug breaks SimpleTest</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/06/php-521-bug-breaks-simpletest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 12:28:10 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/06/php-521-bug-breaks-simpletest/</guid>
      <description>The SimpleTest unit testing and mock object framework for PHP by Marcus Baker at The Last Craft is broken in PHP 5.2.1 due to PHP bug 40768.
The bug causes an infinite loop when &amp;lsquo;break&amp;rsquo; is called in a foreach loop within another foreach loop, when both are looping over variables that internally reference the same array.
&amp;lt;?php $counter = 0; $a = $b = array(1,2,3); foreach ($a as $outer) { echo &amp;#34;$outer, &amp;#34;; if ($counter++ &amp;gt; 10) die(&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 7.04 Feisty Server &amp; Parallels - CDROM/Kernel Workaround</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/05/ubuntu-704-feisty-server-parallels-cdromkernel-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 11:39:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/05/ubuntu-704-feisty-server-parallels-cdromkernel-workaround/</guid>
      <description>Parallels and the Linux 2.6.20 kernel included with the latest Ubuntu release (7.04 - Feisty Fawn) do not get along well. Firstly, the installer fails to detect the CDROM drive emulated by Parallels. Then, if you manage to get Ubuntu installed using a workaround, the server kernel (vmlinuz-2.6.20-16-server) will not boot.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a workaround that I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with to install Ubuntu 7.04 Feisty Fawn Server on Parallels (build 3188). I installed it from the server ISO (ubuntu-7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 7.04 Feisty Fawn on Parallels - CD-ROM Detect Error</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/04/ubuntu-704-feisty-fawn-on-parallels-cd-rom-detect-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2007 06:45:56 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/04/ubuntu-704-feisty-fawn-on-parallels-cd-rom-detect-error/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Solaris CDROM emulation does the trick for Desktop Ubuntu. For Ubuntu Server, read Ubuntu 7.04 Feisty Server &amp;amp; Parallels - CDROM/Kernel Workaround.
If you&#39;re trying to install Ubuntu 7.04 Feisty Fawn on Parallels Desktop for Mac, and getting an error like &#34;No common CD-Rom drive was detected&#34;, this might save you some further googling.
Apparently an issue introduced in some configurations of linux kernel 2.6.20 causes the Parallels emulated CD-ROM to not be detected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lua climbs in TIOBE software index</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/03/lua-climbs-in-tiobe-software-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 02:02:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2007/03/lua-climbs-in-tiobe-software-index/</guid>
      <description>Lua, the lightweight language behind lighttpd&#39;s mod_magnet, has climbed from position 44 to position 25 in the TIOBE Programming Community Index. Maybe we&#39;ll see it in the top 20 soon...
Lua is also a popular language for game scripting engines, perhaps most notably being used in World of Warcraft as an embedded scripting language for the UI subsystem.
Those who get their kicks from network monitoring (such as myself) rather than online gaming may have come across Lua in Wireshark (formerly Ethereal).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static content twice the speed with lighttpd</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/12/static-content-twice-the-speed-with-lighttpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 10:13:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/12/static-content-twice-the-speed-with-lighttpd/</guid>
      <description>I have done a basic benchmark between Apache 2.2 and lighttpd 1.4 for serving the static files on this WordPress installation, using the Apache &amp;ldquo;ab&amp;rdquo; benchmarking tool.
Apache is running prefork MPM, mod_ssl and mod_php5. LightTPD is running with minimal modules loaded for serving static content. Both are running on the same machine, on a Linux 2.6.17 kernel.
Here is the diff of the outputs from each ab benchmark, requesting a static CSS file 10,000 times without HTTP keepalive:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Cookie Limits</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/12/browser-cookie-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 01:36:11 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/12/browser-cookie-limits/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a website where some users have reported their &amp;ldquo;Remember Me&amp;rdquo; session is often being lost by Internet Explorer. The cause appears to be Internet Explorer rejecting cookies beyond a total of 20 for the domain.
Interestingly, Internet Explorer seems to be the only browser to correctly enforce the 20 cookies per domain limit specified by RFC 2965
Here are the limits enforced by the handful of browsers I have tested:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Idea: XML-RPC desktop client/debugger</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/08/project-idea-xml-rpc-desktop-clientdebugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 01:33:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/08/project-idea-xml-rpc-desktop-clientdebugger/</guid>
      <description>While working with XML-RPC in PHP, I&#39;ve been frustrated that the only desktop debugging client I could find was the XML-RPC Client for Mac, which doesn&#39;t do me much good in Windows.
I&#39;m going to try and find time to have a go at building such a tool for Windows, either as a Java application or a XUL Firefox Extension - neither of which I have ever written a useful application with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>for no compelling reason...</title>
      <link>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/07/for-no-compelling-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 04:56:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paul.annesley.cc/2006/07/for-no-compelling-reason/</guid>
      <description>From Netscape&amp;rsquo;s Preliminary Specification for HTTP cookies:
 The state object is called a cookie, for no compelling reason.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>